You have successfully predicted the state mean and covariance matrix.
你已经成功预测了状态均值和协方差矩阵
Terrific, this means we can go into the update step now and
太棒了 这样我们就可以进入更新步骤
predict the measurement.
预测测量值了
This is where we are now.
这是我们现在的位置
We have successfully predicted the state from times step k
我们已经成功预测了从时间步 k 到 k+1 的
to times k step plus one.
状态
Now we have to transform the predicted state into the measurement space.
现在 我们必须把预测状态转换为测量空间
The function that defines this transformation is the measurement model.
定义转换的函数叫做测量模型
Of course, now we have to consider what kind of sensor produced the current
当然 我们现在必须考虑 哪种传感器生成了
measurement and use the corresponding measurement model.
当前测量值 并使用对应的测量模型
The problem we have here is very similar
我们这里的问题和我们在
to the problem we had in the prediction step.
预测步骤碰到的问题非常类似
We need to transform a distribution through a non linear function so
我们需要通过非线性函数来转换一个分布
we can apply exactly the same on center transformation approach
这样我们就能和之前的状态预测一样
as we did before during the state prediction.
在中心变换中应用同样的函数
However, we can take two shortcuts here and make it a little easier.
但是 我们这里有两个捷径 可以更简单一些
Let me show you how.
我们来看看
The first thing we did in the prediction step was generating [INAUDIBLE] points.
我们在预测步骤做的第一件事 就是生成 sigma点
We could do the same here again using the predicted mean and
在这里 我们可以使用预测均值和协方差矩阵
covariance matrix.
同样操作
However, a popular shortcut is
但是 有个常用的快捷方式
to just reuse the signal points we already have from the prediction step.
那就是 只需重用我们在预测步骤已经有的 sigma点即可
So we can skip generating sigma points this time.
因此 我们这次可以跳过生成 sigma点
In this very case, we can also skip the augmentation step.
在这里的情况下 我们还可以跳过扩充步骤
Why is that?
为什么呢？
We needed the augmentation because the process noise
之所以需要扩充 是因为过程噪音
had a non linear effect on the state.
对状态有非线性影响
Let's assume we're talking about a greater measurement in this example.
我们假设 本例中有一个雷达测量值
Here the measurement model was a non linear fraction, but
这里 测量模型是一个非线性函数
the measurement noise had a purely additive effect.
但是测量噪音具备单纯的累加效果
In this case we don't need to perform an augmentation,
在本例中 我们不需要进行扩充
there is an easier way to consider the measurement noise.
测量噪音有更好的处理方法
I will show you later how this works.
后面我会具体说明
So the only thing that's left for us to do is actually transforming
因此 我们只需要做一件事情 就是把已经有的
the individual sigma points we already have into the measurement space and
sigma点转换为测量空间
using them to calculate the mean and
并使用这些店来计算预测测量值的
the covariance matrix S of the predicted measurement.
均值和协方差矩阵 S
Again, we want to store the transformed measurement signal points
同样地 转换后的测量 sigma点
as columns in a matrix.
存储为矩阵中的栏
I call this matrix colorgraphic Z.
我把它记作花体的 Z
Remember the measurement space of the rater.
想想雷达的测量空间
This was the radial distance rho, the angle phi, and
这是径向距离 ρ 角 φ
the radial velocity rho dot, so it is a three dimensional space.
以及径向速度 ρ 点 因此 这是个三维空间
This means the matrix with the measurement sigma points has three rows
这表示 本例中 包括 sigma点的矩阵有 3 行
and 15 columns in our case.
15 列
Regarding for the measurement noise omega,
至于测量噪音 ω
just put in 0 here, since we will account for the measurement noise later.
在这里输入 0 就可以 因为我们后面会处理测量噪音
Now that we have the sigma points and the measurement space, We want to
现在 我们有了 sigma点和测量空间
calculate the resulting mean and covariance of the predicted measurement.
需要计算得到的预测测量值的均值和协方差
This is also very similar as before and given by these equations.
这和之前学过的也很相似 根据这些方程计算即可
The only thing that comes in addition here is that we
这里唯一多出来的是
add the measurement covariance noise.
我们添加了测量协方差噪音
This is how we account for the measurement noise.
这是测量噪音的处理方式
Remember, we can do this instead of the augmentation here,
记住 这里可以使用这个替代扩充
because the measurement noise in our case does not have
因为本例中的测量噪音
a non-linear effect on the measurement but it's purely additive.
对测量不具备非线性效应 它是单纯的累积性的
And that's how you predict the measurement mean and covariance.
这就是预测测量均值和协方差的方式
It's exactly the same problem set as before, but
和之前的问题实际上一样
by using the two sharp cards I just introduced, it is a very easy step.
但借助我刚刚介绍的两个快捷方法 这个步骤非常简单
After this step you have made it almost through the UKF processing chain.
这个步骤完成后 你就几乎已经完成了整个 UKF 处理链